Guide to the Alger Hiss Family Papers TAM.314
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Two grand juries heard Hiss case testimony: the first indicted Hiss on the last day of its existence (December 15, 1948). The second grand jury, empaneled December 16, 1948, continued to question Chambers and other Hiss case witnesses. Seven volumes of transcripts of the grand jury proceedings-from July 1947 through May 1949-were released to the public in 1999 by the National Archives after the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York ordered their release in response to a Public Citizen Litigation Group petition filed on Dec. 15, 1998. Public Citizen represented Bruce Craig when he sued the federal government ( Craig v. USA) for the release of Harry Dexter White's secret grand jury testimony given during the government's investigation into communist and internal subversion. Craig and the litigants won their case resulting in unsealing the White grand jury testimony and other Hiss grand jury related materials. The transcripts consist of approximately 4,000 pages of testimony from a list of witnesses that included Richard Nixon, Alger Hiss, Whittaker Chambers, Harry Dexter White, Congressman Karl E. Mundt, and others.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Series 1, Boxes 1-3; Series 2, Boxes 4-5; and Series 3, Box 6 of the collection are available on microfilm (Film R-7771B) for use in this repository only. Researchers must use microfilm for this portion of the collection.
Personal papers.; Drafts (documents); Correspondence.; Espionage, Soviet -- United States.; Photographs.; Articles.; Legal documents.; Craig, R. Bruce.; Hiss, Priscilla Fansler; Hiss, Tony; Kisseloff, Jeff; Lockwood, Agnese Nelms; Mundt, Karl E.; Navasky, Victor S.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; United Nations; Lowenthal, John, 1925-2003; Communist Party of the United States of America; White, Harry Dexter, 1892-1948; Volkogonov, Dmitri Antonovich.; Smith, John Chabot; Weinstein, Allen; Chambers, Whittaker; Rabinowitz, Victor; Reuben, William A.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1913-2004
  - Correspondence (Letters and Fragments), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, [1929] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1931-Sep 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1931-Nov 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Dec 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1944-Jul 1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Aug 2, 1944-Aug 13, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Aug 14, 1994-Aug 31, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Sep 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1945-May 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1945-Aug 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, Sep 1945-Dec 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1946-Jul 1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1946-Nov 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Dec 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1947-Mar 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1947-May 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, undated, May 1948-Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Sep 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1950-Jul 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1950-Dec 1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1951-May 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1951-Sep 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13, Box Shared Tamiment 209, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1952-Apr 1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, May 1952-Aug 1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Sep 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1953-Mar 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1953-Sep 1953 (Box 2a, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 2a, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1954-Mar 1954 (Box 2a, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1954-Jul 1954 (Box 2a, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 2a, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2a, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2a, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2a, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2a, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1959-Jul 1959 (Box 2a, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1959-Dec 1959 (Box 2a, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2a, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2a, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2a, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2a, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2a, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2a, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2a, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2a, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2a, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2a, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2a, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2a, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2a, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1996-Sep 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1892-2003
  - Alger Hiss and the Panama Canal Zone (typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bowie, F.M.: United States Department of Agriculture, Memorandum to Miss Phillips, Jan 1934 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chabot Smith, John: Alger Hiss: The True Story, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, undated, 1979, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Choate, Hall and Stewart: Illegality of Plaintiff's Business as Defense in a Triple Damage Suit (Raytheon Case), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Choate, Hall and Stewart: Memorandum for Mr. Nash Re: Establishment of Cambridge School at Weston, Nov 25, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland: Graphic Designer/Printer, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Cold War and the Constitution - Chapter XXIII (unidentified typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Jordan-Lyman Company Inc. v. Samuel Rottenburg, Oct 1930-Nov 1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Natalie M. Steene v. General Office Equipment Corporation, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Contra-Hiss: Articles/Clippings, 1971, 1976, 1992-1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, 1930s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cotton, Franklin, Wright and Gordon: Memorandum Re: RCA v. Cable Radio Tube Corporation, Jan 4, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fansler, Thomas: Autobiography, "A True Story of an Illinois Farmer" (typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fansler, Thomas: Elected Evanston, Illinois City Treasurer, Apr 22, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Faulk, John Henry, 1960, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Forged Typed Evidence (excerpt from unidentified book), undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Federal Prisons: Articles and Pamphlets, Photocopied, 1936, 1942-1960s, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Field, Richard: Report to Contributors to the Defense Fund for Alger Hiss, Feb 17, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Geismar, Maxwell: Letter to the New York Review of Books re: Chambers, Apr 21, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Haggerty, James C.: Statement Regarding Hiss and Nixon, Nov 18, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Halper, Albert: "Whittaker Chambers on 14th Street," from Good-bye to Union Square, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hiss, Alger: American Bar Association, Membership Card, Jan 27, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hiss, Alger: American Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc., 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hiss, Alger: Annual Conference of the American Society for Public Administration, Mar 14, 1947-Mar 16, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hiss, Alger: Appointments and Telephone Messages, 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hiss, Alger: Bank Pass Books, 1900s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hiss, Alger: Biographical and Hiss Case, 1924-1999 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hiss, Alger: Calling Cards and Notes, undated, 1945-1947, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hiss, Alger: College Lecture Itineraries, Royce Carlton, Inc., undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Hiss, Alger: College Lecture Itineraries, Royce Carlton, Inc., 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Hiss, Alger: Excerpts from Consent Decrees (typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Hiss, Alger: Foreign Policy Association, Membership Card, 19448-1949 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Hiss, Alger: Fuel Oil Ration, Jul 1945 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Hiss, Alger: Handwritten Notes, undated, 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Hiss, Alger: International Student Identity Card, Apr 1929 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Hiss, Alger: Interview with Anthony Wedgwood Benn (BBC), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Hiss, Alger: Lectures/Speaking Engagements, undated, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Hiss, Alger: Meetings of the Committee to Make Recommendations as to the use of the Holmes' Bequest, 1939, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memoranda for Mr. Bundy, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memoranda for Mr. Gordon, Includes Handwritten Notes, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memoranda for Mr. Pengra, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum, Cases on Conditions Precedent in Surety Bonds, Jan 16, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Blair, Jan 18, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Garfield, Nov 25, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Hall, Includes Handwritten Notes, Nov 1930 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Jenckes, Includes Handwritten Notes, Dec 9, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Knowlton, Nov 15, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Knowlton Re: Merchants National Bank of Boston, Handwritten Notes, Oct 29, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Nash, May 1, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. C.C. Parlin, Jun 13, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Proctor Re: John Healey Application for Naturalization, Nov 1930 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Rand, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Sherburne, Kelvinator Sales Corporation, Oct 30, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Wentworth, Jan 5, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum for Mr. Wentworth, Includes Handwritten Notes, Nov 1, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum, U.S. v. RCA et al., Nov 2, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum, Walker v. Man, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Hiss, Alger: Memorandum Re: Butter, Egg, Cheese and Poultry Industries (Pacific Coast), Handwritten Notes, Jul 7, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Hiss, Alger: Notice of Official Efficiency Rating, Jun 17, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Hiss, Alger: Obituaries, Nov 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Hiss, Alger: Office Memorandum, Accumulated Leave, Dec 13, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Hiss, Alger: Open Price Trade Association, Handwritten Notes, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Hiss, Alger: Preliminary Memorandum Re: Torquay v. RCA et al., Jan 24, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Hiss, Alger: Promissory Note and Guaranty to Mrs. Mary L. Hiss, Feb 1, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Hiss, Alger: Readmission to Massachusetts State Bar, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Hiss, Alger: Statement of Duties, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Hiss, Alger: Statement Made under Oath before the House Committee on Un-American Activities, Aug 5, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Hiss, Alger: Statements, undated, Mar 18, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Hiss, Alger: Travel Vouchers, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Hiss, Alger: Vaccination Records, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Hiss, Alger: Various Legal Cases (Notes), 1925 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Court Cases: "Excerpts from Leading Cases Applicable to Issues in the Case of US vs. RCA et al." [Misfiled during Microfilming], Nov 4, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Hiss, Alger: Writings, 1973, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Hiss, Anna: Defense Stamp Album, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Hiss, Philip Hanson, Jr., Feb 28, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Hiss, Tony: Hand-written Notes, undated, 1988, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Hiss, Tony: Harvard College, Jun 21, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Hiss, Tony: Laughing Last, Invitation, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Hiss, Tony: New Yorker article, "My Father's Honor", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Hiss, Tony: New Yorker article, "My Father's Honor" (Correspondence Re:), Nov 1992-Dec 1992 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Hiss, Tony: The View from Alger's Window(edited typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Hiss, Tony: War Ration Books, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Hiss, Tony: Writings, 1973, 1996, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Hiss Case: Clippings, 1950, 1970-1977, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Hiss Case: Clippings, 1982, 1988, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Hiss Case: Clippings, 1996, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Hiss Case: "Pumpkin Papers", 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Hiss Case: Reopening of, 1971-1983, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Hiss Case: Theater and Television, 1976, 1984-1985, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Hiss Case: "Trial by Perjury: A New Look at the Case Which Ruined the Life of Alger Hiss" (2pp. typescript), undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Hiss Case: Typewriter, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Hiss, Donald, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Hiss Family: Memorabilia/Ephemera, undated, 1933-1949, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Hiss, Mary L.: Estate of, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Hiss, Mike: "Hiss Named Top Rookie by United States Auto Club", undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Hiss, Priscilla Fansler, 1942-1968 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Hobson, Laura Z., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Hobson, Timothy: Subpoena and Summons, Aug 1948, Dec 1948 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Huberman, Leo: Statement Regarding Alger Hiss, May 5, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Lake, Anthony, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - La Pointe, Terrance: "An Open Letter to and about Alger Hiss", May 17, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Levine, David, Apr 25, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lewisburg Prison: Images (photocopies), undated, Jul 1947, Oct 1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lowenthal, John, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lowenthal, John: Funeral and Obituaries, Sep 2003-Nov 2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Lowenthal, John: Interview with Ella Winter, Feb 6, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - McGovern, George: "Nixon and Historical Memory", Mar 1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - McLaughlin, Donal, Jan 17, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Murphy, Robert C.: "The Hiss Case: Insights", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Foundation: Hiss Case, Statements, 1975, 1978, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Navasky, Victor, Nov 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul: Manuscript for Simon and Schuster, Draft Pages, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - One World, A Forum of Federalist Opinion: "L'Affaire Hiss" (pamphlet), Feb 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Poem: "Supplement to Reorganization Order" (Humorous Farewell to Alger Hiss), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Proposal for Private Meetings on Foreign Policy, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Reuben, William A., undated, 1975, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, undated, 1946, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Salant, Steven W.: Interview with Donald T. Appell, Sep 24, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Stryker, Paul Lloyd: Clipping (annotated), [Aug 1995] (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Supreme Court, New York County: Radio Corporation of America v. Cable Radio Tube Corporation, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Syracuse University: The Maxwell Graduate School of Citizenship and Public Affairs, May 17, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Theoharis, Athan: Article on Hiss case ( Intellect Magazine), Sep 1975-Oct 1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Unger, Craig: "Wright or Wrong" ( The Real Paper), Oct 3, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified Typescript: Alger Hiss as a Salesman, Apr 11, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - United Nations, undated, Jun 1944-Jul 1944, 1985-1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - United Nations: Conference and Secretariat Personnel, Apr 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - United Nations: Conference, Charts, undated, May 5, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - United Nations: Conference, Hiss Schedule, May 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - United Nations: Conference, Proposed Rules of Procedure, Apr 20, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - United Nations: Conference on International Organization, Jun 1945 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - United Nations: Conference, Per Diem and Hotel Expenses, Apr 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - United Nations: Draft Report from the Coordination Committee to the Executive Committee, [1945] (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - United Nations: U.S. Activity toward Establishment of International Organizations, Apr 17, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - United States Department of Justice: "Federal Offenders, 1932-1933", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - United States District Court, Southern District of New York: F.J. Rooney Lamp Company v. Radio Corporation of America, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - United States District Court, Southern District of New York: Hugo Cohn v. Cities Service Company, Jan 30, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - United States Government: Office Memorandum, Positions in the Rockefeller Foundation, May 29, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Venona Documents, about, 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Volkogonov, Dmitri, 1992-1993, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, Mar 7, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Weinstein, Allen, undated, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Wishnatsky, Martin: "The State Department" with Hiss's Annotations, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Zeligs, Meyer, 1960-1967 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Series III: Crimea Conference Scrapbook, 1945
  - Crimea Conference [aka Yalta Conference]: Scrapbook (Note: R-7771B/13 Begins Here), Feb 1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series IV: Non-Microfilmed Correspondence and Subject Files, 1931-2003
  - The Alger Hiss Story: Website, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Anna Hiss Women's Gymnasium, University of Texas at Austin: Controversy, re:, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Barnum, Thomas J.: "Isaac Don Levine, The Key Man Behind the Hiss Case" (notes), Jan 16, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington: Percent Fluctuations of Dividends, May 1947 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland: "Progress in the Graphic Arts" signed "For my friend Alger Hiss with warm regard and great respect", Dec 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1951, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6a)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 6b)
  - Correspondence, Nov 1, 1996-Nov 17, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Nov 18, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Nov 19, 1996-Nov 20, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Nov 21, 1996-Nov 24, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Nov 25, 1996-Nov 30, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Dec 1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Dec 1997 - Nov 1998, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Council on Foreign Relations: By-Laws, Jan 1945 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Hiss, Alger: Field, Noel Documents, 1986-1988 (Box Shared Tamiment MS002)
  - Hiss, Alger: Funeral, re:, Dec 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hiss, Alger: Interview with James S. Sutterlin (Photocopy of an original in the United Nations Archives), Feb 13, 1990; Oct 11, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15a)
  - Hiss, Alger: Interview with Isabel Grossner (photocopy of an original from Columbia University Oral History Research Office), 1969 (Box 7, Folder 15b)
  - Hiss, Alger: Interview with Timmerman Daughtery (Correspondence) (Includes correspondence from Alger Hiss), 1979-1989, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 15c)
  - Hiss, Alger: "The Pumpkin Papers Introduced and Explained" ( The Real World), Feb 1976-Mar 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Hiss, Alger: "Reminiscences of Alger Hiss," oral history conducted by Edward Robb Ellis (photocopy of an original from Columbia University Oral History Research Office), 1975-1983 (Box 7, Folder 16a)
  - Hiss Case: Government's Exhibits Received in Evidence, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Coram Nobis, 1978, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Family: Biographical Information, 1940s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Hiss, Tony: FBI, FOIA, and Prison Research re: Alger Hiss, 1930s, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Hiss, Tony: The New Yorker, Correspondence, re:, 1998-1999 (Box 7A, Folder 1)
  - Hiss, Tony: Prison History, 1992-1993 (Box 7A, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Gerald: New Republic Article (Abbreviation), Apr 16, 1962 (Box 7A, Folder 3)
  - Legislative History of Title I of the Agricultural Adjustment Act, undated (Box 7A, Folder 4)
  - Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (Box 7A, Folder 5)
  - Levin, David: Forms of Uncertainty: Essays in Historical Criticism, Chapter re: Hiss (Book Excerpt), 1992 (Box 7A, Folder 6)
  - Levine, Isaac Don: Biographical Information, undated (Box 7A, Folder 7)
  - Lewin, John Henry: "The Associated Press Decision-An Extension of the Sherman Act?" (signed) ( University of Chicago Law Review), Apr 1946 (Box 7A, Folder 8)
  - Lippman, Walter: "The Tennessee Case," (clipping), 1962 (Box 7A, Folder 9)
  - Lowenthal, John: "Venona and Alger Hiss" ( Intelligence and National Security), 2000 (Box 7A, Folder 10)
  - Mischler, Amy: Alger Hiss Term Paper, 1997 (Box 7A, Folder 11)
  - Moore, Ben T.: "1945" (typescript), undated (Box 7A, Folder 12)
  - New York State Bar Association: Report of the Committee on International Law, Jan 24, 1947-Jan 24, 1947 (Box 7A, Folder 13)
  - Preparation of Clause 9 Triple Damage Cases, Oct 1, 1929 (Box 7A, Folder 14)
  - Room 3603 and Witness: Book Excerpts, 1952, 1962 (Box 7A, Folder 15)
  - Russell, Jessica: The Press and Alger Hiss(abstract), Aug 1975 (Box 7A, Folder 16)